Cecilia was the first to go.
西西莉亚是第一个“身体力行”的
What are you doing here? You're not old enough to know how bad life gets.
你在干什么，丫头 你还小，还不懂什么是人生苦短
Obviously, doctor, you've never been a 13-year-old girl.
大夫，显而易见 你不是13岁的女生
Everyone dates the demise of our neighborhood
自从里斯本家的女孩们开始了 这种自杀的行为
from the suicides of the Lisbon girls.
我们这些邻居都在见证着 他们的“死亡之路”
People saw their clairvoyants in the wiped out elms, the harsh sunlight,
人们努力洞察着一切 透过衰竭的榆树、透过刺眼的阳光…
and the continuing decline of our auto industry.
…还有我们那日益破败的汽车工业
Even then we tried putting the pieces together.
即便我们试图 将种种可能拼凑到一起
We still can't.
可还是无能为力
Whenever we meet at business lunches or cocktail parties
现在无论是商务午餐还是鸡尾酒会
we go over the evidence one more time.
只要能聚到一起 我们就会谈论这事件的种种迹象
All to understand those five girls,
所有这一切都是为了 了解他们五姐妹
who, after all these years, we can't get out of our minds.
他们…是我们多年以来 挥之不去的记忆
Cecilia, the youngest, was 1 2.
西西莉亚，老幺，12岁
And Lux was 1 4.
拉克斯，14岁
Bonnie was 1 5.
邦妮，15
Mary was 16.
玛莉，16
And Therese was 1 7.
还有特瑞斯，17
No one understood how Mr Lisbon, our Math teacher,
没人明白我们的算术老师 里斯本先生
had produced such beautiful creatures.
怎么会拥有如此的天生尤物
Paul Baldino said he found Cecilia on her first attempt.
保罗 包迪诺说 他是在第一次搞偷摸的时候 发现了西西莉亚
l was the one who found her.
是我发现了她
l was in the sewers. Through those tunnels you can get into anyone's house.
那时我正在我家的下水道 从那些管道你想去哪儿就去哪儿
We believed him because Paul's dad was Sammy the Shark Baldino
我们相信他所说的 因为他爸当过兵，绰号“鲨鱼老包”
and his escape tunnel led through the sewers.
他们家的防空洞直通到下水道
So l wanted to see one of those lesbian girls taking a shower.
所以我想瞧瞧那些 里斯本家的“女同”们洗澡的样子
Yeah, right.
是啊，没错
And l walk in... And l see blood everywhere!
然后我就进去了… 然后我就看见到处是血！
So l turned around and went right back out the tunnel.
那我只好打道回府喽 钻回管道，然后出来
l had to tell you guys that story. See you guys later.
我会给你们讲完这故事的 回头见，伙计们
l heard it was an accident.
我听说是事故
lt was no accident. The parents are to blame.
不，那可不是事故 他们父母应该受到谴责
l heard they found the razor in the toilet.
我听说他们在厕所里发现了剃须刀
Everyone had opinions why Cecilia tried to kill herself.
每个人都对西西莉亚伤害自己的行为 有一套自己的看法
That girl didn't want to die, she just wanted out of that house.
那丫头不是想死，她只是想离开那房子
She wanted out of that decorating scheme.
她讨厌那些装饰的色调搭配
The most popular theory held Dominic Palazzolo to blame.
最普遍的看法是 多米尼克 帕拉佐罗有一定责任
Dominic was an immigrant who was staying with relatives
多米尼克是中美移民 一直和亲戚住在一起
until his family got settled in New Mexico.
直到他们家在新墨西哥扎了根 他才离开
He was the first boy here to wear sunglasses.
他是这儿第一个戴太阳镜的男孩
Within a week of arriving he'd fallen in love.
来这的第一个星期，他恋爱了
The object of his desire wasn't Cecilia, but Diana Porter.
他心驰的对象并非西西利亚 而是黛安娜 波特
l love her!
我爱她!
When Diana Porter left on vacation, Dominic denounced God.
在黛安娜 波特渡假离开的时候 多米尼克当众指责上帝
And to prove his love, he jumped off the roof of his relatives' house.
并且为了证明他的真心 他从亲戚家的屋顶上跳了下去
l'm going to show you some images.
我要给你看一些图片
And... er, you tell me
然后…嗯，你告诉我…
what they remind you of.
他们让你想到了什么
OK?
OK？
A banana.
香蕉
A swamp.
沼泽
An Afro.
泡面头
l don't think that Cecilia truly meant to end her life.
我认为西西莉亚无意了结自己的生命
Her act was a cry for help.
她的行为是一种寻求帮助的呐喊
l know you're very strict,
我知道你们非常严格
but l think that Cecilia would benefit
不过我想如果西西莉亚
by having a social outlet outside of the codification of school.
接受一些学校繁文缛节外的 社交经验会获益颇多
And interact with males her own age.
还有，多和她同龄的男孩们接触
Peter helped Mr Lisbon install a model of the solar system in his classroom.
彼得帮助里斯本先生在他班里 安装了一套模拟太阳系的模型
ln return, Mr Lisbon invited him for dinner.
作为回报，里斯本先生邀请他吃晚餐
Bless us, O Lord, in these, Thy gifts
赐福我们，主啊 感谢您，将这些…
which we receive from Thy bounty through Christ. Amen.
基督慷慨施舍的礼物赐予我们 阿门
- Lux, please put your shirt on this instant. - Sorry.
- 拉克斯，请你穿上外衫，现在 - 抱歉
- Thank you, dear. - Can you pass the salt, please?
- 谢谢，亲爱的 - 能不能把盐递给我，谢谢？
- Ham? - Thank you.
- 汉姆？ - 谢谢
- Sweetheart, would you like some peas? - l hate peas.
- 亲爱的，要不要青豆？ - 我讨厌青豆
lt's a nice-looking ham, dear.
汉姆，今天穿的挺帅
- Well, thank you, honey. - This is good, mum.
- 喔，谢谢，亲爱的 - 这个不错，老妈
So, Peter, are you an aviation enthusiast?
那么，彼得 你热衷于航空学喽？
Well, l don't know if l'd call myself an enthusiast.
呃，我不知道自己算不算热衷
l like planes.
我喜欢飞机
Peter, are you on the football squad?
彼得，你是橄榄球队的吗？
No. l play, but l'm not on the team.
不，我玩玩，但是没有入队
- Oh, l see. - Not a team player.
- 哦，明白了 - 还不是队员
Do you like to wrestle?
喜欢摔角吗？
Are you OK?
你还好吧？
A Brazilian frog entered the endangered species list today.
今天，一种巴西青蛙 列入濒临绝种的动物名单
- That's the third animal this year. - Oh, dear. Darling, l've never heard of it.
- 这是今年第3个列入名单的动物 - 哦，亲爱的，宝贝儿，我才听说
- Excuse me. May l use the restroom? - Of course.
- 不好意思，我能用一下盥洗室吗？ - 当然
The one down here isn't working. Go upstairs through Cecilia's room.
楼下的不好用了 上楼吧，过了西西莉亚的房间就是
OK, thanks.
OK，谢谢
Hold on.
等等
l thought you'd died in there.
我以为你死在里面了
Are you done hogging the bathroom? l need something.
占领洗手间的游戏结束了没？ 我需要点东西
Do you mind?
不介意的话…
- Thank you. - Are you forgetting something?
- 万分感谢 - 忘了什么东西了？
- Peter, here's an air foil... - Thank you.
- 彼得，来看看这个机翼… - 谢谢您，再见
lt's a demonstration of Bernoulli's Principle.
是根据柏努利的理论制作的
Lift...
抬升…
From then on the Lisbon house began to change.
从那以后，里斯本家开始发生了变化
Almost every day, and even when she wasn't keeping an eye on Cecilia,
几乎每一天，只要拉克斯 不用看护西西莉亚，
Lux would suntan on her towel, wearing a swimsuit
她就会穿上泳装 躺在浴巾上，享受太阳浴
that caused the knife-sharpener to give her a 1 5-minute demonstration for free.
这导致的结果是，磨刀师傅答应 给她做15分钟的免费指导
Following the doctor's orders, two weeks after Cecilia returned home
为谨遵医嘱 西西莉亚回家两星期后
Mr Lisbon persuaded his wife to let the girls throw the only party of their short lives.
里斯本先生说服了太太 允许女儿们举行了 他们短暂生命中仅有的一次派对
There. ls that OK?
这样，行不行？
l've got to get dressed.
我应该衣装打扮了
- Welcome. - Good evening, Mrs Lisbon.
- 欢迎光临 - 晚上好，里斯本夫人
Come on in.
进来吧
The party's in the basement.
派对在地下室
Just go to the left and then down the stairs.
只须向左转，下台阶就是
Hi, l'm Bonnie.
嗨，我是邦妮
- Hi... Tim. - Nice to meet you.
- 嗨…蒂姆 - 高兴见到你
- Would you like some punch? - Yeah.
- 要点鲜榨汁吗？ - 好的
Thanks.
谢谢
- Hi. - Thanks.
- 嗨 - 多谢
- Thank you.
- 谢谢
- Hey. - Hi.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Do you want to sit down? - Yeah.
- 想坐下来吗？ - 是啊
- How did your SATs go? - OK.
- 你的SAT（学术才能测验，美国高考） 考得怎么样 - OK
Good.
很好
Do you know where you're applying yet?
知道录取结果了吗？
No, but my parents are pushing towards Yale.
还没有，不过我父母希望我进“耶鲁”
- Because that's where my dad went. - That's nice.
- 因为我爸爸是那儿毕业的 - 真不错
You have to imagine the clouds opening up
试着想象一下，云开雾散…
and out of the sun would come the Hun in his Messerschmitt.
…从太阳中冲出来的 就是这架敌机，梅式战斗机
And boys, just older than you, would be in this, the P51 B Mustang.
还有，小伙子们，比你大2、3岁的 都会驾驶这架P51 B 外号“野马”
''B'' for bull's-eye.
“B”代表什么？代表公牛的眼睛
- You've heard of Yale? - Oh, yeah.
- 听说过“耶鲁”没？ - 哦，是的
- This punch is fantastic. - More?
- 这鲜榨汁真棒 - 还要些吗？
What's in it?
里面有什么？
Juices, some cherry... pineapple.
果汁，樱桃…菠萝
You know, l... l love pineapple.
你知道吗？我…我喜欢菠萝
Really?
真的？
This baby would come in. This won the war for the United Kingdom.
这宝贝要是参战 肯定替大英帝国赢得这场战役
- Excuse me. - Sure.
- 不好意思 - 没什么
And it's this kind of equipment that makes a model work.
看，是类似这样的装备 来保证模型正常运转的
Here's Joe.
这位是乔
- Hi, Joe. - Hi.
- 嗨，乔 - 嗨
- lf he needs anything, call me. - l'm sure he'll be fine.
- 如果他需要什么，跟我说 - 我保证他会很自在的
- Hi.
- 嗨
Joe. Good to see you. How are you?
乔，很高兴见到你，最近怎么样？
- Glad you came tonight. - How's it going?
- 很高兴你今晚能来 - 怎么样？
You're just in time.
来得刚刚好
Hi.
嗨
Look. His ears go if you scratch his chin.
大家看，刮他下巴，耳朵就会动
Joe, sing your song.
乔，唱支歌吧
Oh, the monkeys have no tails in Zamboanga
哦，三宝颜的猴子没有尾巴
They were bitten off by whales
哦，猴子没有尾巴 是鲸鱼咬掉的
Oh, the monkeys have no tails in Zamboanga
哦，三宝颜的猴子没有尾巴
- Good song. - Good job, Joe.
- 歌不错 - 干得不赖，乔
Where'd you learn that song?
哪学的这歌？
Can l be excused?
我要受到惩罚吗？
lf you want to, my dear, but this is your party.
除非你想，亲爱的 这是你的晚会
All right. lf you want to go upstairs, do. We'll just...
好吧，如果你想上楼去 那就去吧。我们只好…
We'll just have to have fun without you.
我们只好在没有你的情况下 乐不思蜀了
Look. He always chooses heads.
看着，他只会选“头”
- Joe, what's it going to be? - Heads.
- 乔，会是什么？ - 头
Joe, try tails.
乔，试试“字”
Heads it is!
真的是头！
- Let's go. - Heads.
- 再来了 - 头
Heads! One more time.
头！再来一次
- ln the air, Joe. - Heads.
- 空中猜，乔 - 头
Heads it is!
还是头！
- One more time. Call in the air, Joe. - Heads.
- 再来一次，在空中叫出来，乔 - 头
Heads. Not bad.
头，真不赖
- How are you doing? - Good.
- 你怎么样？ - 很好
- He picked it up really well. - This is my favorite song.
- 他这歌选的不错 - 是我最喜欢的
You know, you're... very beautiful. Like a saint.
知道吗？你…非常漂亮 好像圣女一样
l could paint you some time.
我会挑个时间来描述你的样子
Thanks.
谢了
Did they sing it?
- 他们也唱这个吗？ - 是的
Wow, that's good!
哇哦，好极了！
God!
上帝啊！
Oh, Lord!
哦，天啊！
Cecilia!
西西莉亚！
Oh, my...! No! No, no, no!
哦，我的…不！不，不，不！
Don't look. Turn around.
别看！转过去
Turn around! Darlings, turn... Oh, my God!
转过去，亲爱的孩子们，转… 哦，我的上帝
Oh, Jesus!
哦，耶稣保佑
Please, God.
求你保佑，上帝
We're here now.
我们来了
No funerals today.
今天没有葬礼 （墓地的人在罢工，要求福利）
He said she was only 1 2.
他说她只有12岁
Hi, Mary. Are your parents home?
嗨，玛莉，你父母在吗？
Hi, Father. Come in.
嗨，神父，请进
Oh. Hello, Father.
哦，你好，神父
Please, sit down.
请坐
Thanks.
谢谢
Come on, that was inside!
哦，少来了，那球在界内
Uh, no. No, thanks.
呃，不，不，谢谢了
How about we get the missus down here? Have a little chat?
不如我们请尊夫人下来 稍谈片刻
l'm afraid she's under the weather.
恐怕不行，这天气让她不舒服
She's not...
她不见...
seeing anybody.
任何人
Well, she'll see her priest.
也许，她会想见她的牧师
This kid's a sucker for the inside ones every time.
这孩子是个笨蛋 每次都把界内球判断错
Every time.
每次
Excuse me.
打扰了
Father...
神父…
Double play, Father.
双杀，神父
Double play.
双杀
Mrs Lisbon?
里斯本太太？
- May l come in? - OK.
- 我可以进来吗？ - OK
Hello, girls. l thought we could talk.
你们好，姑娘们 我想我们能聊聊
Do you feel like talking?
想聊聊吗？
Well... if you ever want to,
好吧…如果你们想聊的话…
you know where to find me.
知道上哪儿找我，对吧
Mrs Lisbon? lt's Father Moody.
里斯本太太？我是穆迪神父
Mrs Lisbon. Hello.
里斯本太太，你好
l wanted you to know that l listed Cecilia's death as an accident.
我想让你知道 我把西西莉亚的死归为一次偶然事故
An accident waiting to happen.
一次等待发生的偶然事故？
- They couldn't get a policy to cover it. - lt's incredibly dangerous.
- 他们没有合适的理由掩盖真相 - 实在太危险
Let's give it a try.
来试试看吧
Ready? One, two, three.
准备，一、二、三
lt's so sad, l can't believe it happened.
真令人难过，难以相信居然会发生
Have you got that chain in your truck?
你卡车里有锁链吗？
Hit it!
拖！
Our collection of souvenirs of the Lisbon girls -
我们收藏下来 现在还保留着的――
which still exists - started with Cecilia's diary.
“里斯本家女孩”的纪念品―― 就从西西莉亚的日记开始吧
Parkie had gotten it from the plumber's assistant, who'd found it in the bathroom.
日记是帕奇从水管工那里得到的 据说是在卧室发现的
Tim Weiner, the Brain, decoded it.
蒂姆 维那，绰号“智囊” 破译了它的内容
Emotional instability.
情绪的不稳定化
Look at the ''ls'', the dots on them. They're everywhere.
看看这个“是”字，上面点了很多点 到处都是
Basically, what we have here is a dreamer.
基本上，我们这里看到的 是个空想家
Someone completely out of touch with reality.
一个和现实完全没有接触的人
When she jumped, she probably thought she would fly.
她跳下去的时候 很有可能以为自己会飞
Monday, February 1 2th. Today we had frozen pizza.
2月12日，周一 今天，我们吃的是冻批萨
Thursday. Mum made cream corn for dinner. lt's the worst. lt looks like...
周四，晚上吃的是妈妈做的奶油玉米 这是最糟的晚餐，看上去就像…
Mary chipped a tooth acting like an idiot.
玛莉咬碎了自己的牙齿 活像个傻瓜
She made a scene and had to get her tooth capped.
她大吵大闹了一通 最后还是要镶牙
- lt looks normal. - Give me that.
- 看上去挺普通阿 - 给我看
l said she had a capped tooth.
我说她镶了一颗牙吧
Elm trees! How many pages can you write about dying trees?
榆树！ 如果让你写要死的树，能写多少页？
Here's something about Dominic.
这儿，是关于多米尼克的
Palazzolo jumped off the roof today over that rich bitch, Porter.
帕拉佐罗今天从屋顶上跳下来 还跳过了那个有钱的婊子，波特
How stupid can you be?
你真是有够蠢！
Today we went out on the boat. lt was cold. We saw a couple of whales.
今天我们出海了，很冷 不过我们看到了很多鲸鱼
Lux stroked the whale. l didn't think they'd stink so much.
拉克斯还摸了其中的一头 我觉得他们身上的味道不怎么重
lt's the kelp in their bellies rotting.
应该是他们肚子里腐烂的水草味儿
l hope we can go again some time.
我希望有时间还能再玩一次
Let's read that.
来读这个
Lux lusted over Kevin... ls it ''Heinz''? The garbage man.
拉克斯勾引了凯文…这写的是“Heinz”吗？ 那个垃圾工
Lux lusted over Kevin Haines, the garbage man.
拉克斯勾引了凯文 汉斯
She'd wake up at 5am and hang out on the front steps.
她会在5点醒来 然后在前廊的台阶上遛Q
Like it wasn't completely obvious!
好让这种行为看上去完全不露痕迹
She wrote his name on all her underwear.
她在她所有的内裤上都写了他的名字
Mum found them and bleached out all the Kevins.
妈妈发现了这事 就把那些写有凯文的字都漂干净了
Lux is crying on her bed all day.
拉克斯为此在床上哭了一整天
''The trees, like lungs filling with air
“那些树，像肺叶充斥在空气中
''My sister, the mean one, pulling my hair''
“我的姐姐 ―讨厌的那个― 揪下了我的头发
And so we started to learn about their lives.
因此我们开始研究他们的生活
Coming to hold the memories of times we hadn't experienced.
慢慢的，我们追寻起过去时光的记忆 一种我们从未经历过的时光
We felt the imprisonment of being a girl.
我们感觉到了作为女孩子的束缚
How it made your mind active and dreamy.
这束缚影响了 他们的头脑如何思维和幻梦
And how you learnt what colors went together.
还影响了他们如何决定 颜色的归属
We knew that the girls were really women in disguise.
我们知道了女孩子 其实就是伪饰过的女人
They understood love and even death.
他们明白爱，甚至死亡
Our job was to create the noise that fascinated them.
而我们的任务是制造喧嚣 来取悦他们
They knew everything about us, but we couldn't fathom them at all.
我们晓得他们知道我们的一切 而我们根本无法看透他们
Hi. Mrs Lisbon, l'm Lydia Perl. l'm putting together...
嗨，里斯本太太，我是莉迪娅 珀尔 我整理了一些…
- Oh! - Hi, l'm Bonnie. This is Mary.
- 哦！ - 嗨，我叫邦妮，这是玛莉
Hello, girls. l'm here to ask you a couple of questions...
你们好，姑娘们，我来这儿 是想问你们几个问题的
about Cecilia.
关于西西莉亚的
- Yeah? - Great. Um...
- 好的？ - 很好，蕖
Maybe you could tell me a little bit about her?
或许你们可以透露一些关于她的情况
Did she have any special interests or hobbies?
她有没有一些特别的兴趣或者爱好
She liked writing her journal a lot.
她喜欢记很多的日记
That is great.
很好
OK. Did she...
OK，她有没有…
Did she ever talk about ending her life?
有没有谈到过要结束自己的生命
What's going on here?
这儿怎么了？
You must be Mrs Lisbon.
您就是里斯本太太吧？
l'm Lydia Perl. l'm doing a piece for Channel Two.
我是莉迪娅 珀尔 在二频道工作
You have to leave now, Miss Perl.
您得离开了，珀尔小姐
The suicide of a teenager last summer has increased the awareness of a crisis.
去年暑假一个12岁少女的死 增加了对一种危机的认知
l'm at the home where Cecilia Lisbon...
我现在就在西西莉亚 里斯本的家
Why don't they let her rest in peace?
他们为什么不能给她一些安宁呢？
..tragically put an end to her life.
…悲剧性的结束了她的生命
Psychologists agree that adolescence today
心理学家认为 今天处于青春期的孩子们
is more fraught by pressures and complexities than in years past.
和过去相比 面临更多的压力和复杂的事物
Doctors say that frustration can lead to acts of violence
越来越多的医生们认为 这种挫折感会导致暴力行为
whose reality the adolescent cannot separate from its intended drama.
原因是青少年无法将现实生活同 戏剧性的故事情节割裂开来
l baked a pie full of rat poison.
我烘了一个派，上面全是老鼠药
l thought l could eat it without it being suspicious.
我觉得我会吃掉它 你知道，在没有人怀疑的前提下
My nana, who was 86...
我的奶奶，86岁…
She really likes sweets.
她最喜欢吃甜食
She had three pieces.
她吃了3块
l'm sorriest for the mother.
我对那母亲感到万分遗憾
You'd always wonder what you could have done.
我理解 你会经常想，本应该早做些什么的
- l gotta go. See you later. - All right. Bye-bye.
- 好了，我要走了，回头见 - 好的，拜拜
Bye-bye.
拜拜
Don't worry.
别担心
They took the fence out.
他们拖走篱栏了
God, you snore loud.
天啊，你鼾声如雷
Those girls have a bright future ahead.
那些姑娘们会有远大前程的
The other one was just going to end up a cook.
另外的那个只是去赴别人的晚餐罢了
We didn't see the girls together as a group until September 7th.
直到9月7号我们才看见姑娘们 成群结队的来学校
Mary, Lux, Bonnie and Therese,
玛莉、拉克斯、邦妮和特瑞斯
came to school as though nothing had happened.
好像什么都没发生过
We felt if we looked hard, we'd understand their feelings and who they were.
我们感觉如果努力观察， 会了解他们的感受，还有他们到底是谁
All right. These are Venn diagrams, as you remember.
好吧，如果你们还有印象的话 这就是维恩图解
lf we have ''A'' and ''B'' intersecting. And ''A'' and ''B''.
如果有集合A和集合B，两者相交 以及这个集合A和集合B
lf ''A'' intersects ''B'', we have this area.
如果求集合A和集合B的交集 会得到这个区域
And if ''A'' is the union with ''B'', we have all of the circle plus the intersection.
而如果求集合A和集合B的并集 我们得到的是 这个圆圈内所有的再加上交集的部分
These are the laws of intersection and union. OK?
这些是交集和并集的规则，OK？
How's it going?
你怎么样？
Not bad.
不坏
OK. ''Do a character sketch on the following characters from Portrait Of A Lady...''
OK“根据A女士的对下列人物的描述 勾勒出她所形容的对象…”
The first one is... Ralph.
首先是…拉尔夫
Um... He was nice.
呃…他挺好
lt was really sad when he died.
他死得时候真的很悲伤
Oh, my gosh. l can't believe l just said that.
哦，我的天 难以相信我刚才那么说
l am so sorry.
我非常抱歉
Reading about the alarming suicide rate,
读了那篇关于自杀死亡率的文章 真是令人担忧
l talked to Mr Woodhouse and some of the teachers here
我和伍德豪斯先生 还有这里的其他一些老师谈论了一下
and realized that nothing about this serious matter has been discussed at this school.
意识到在这所学校 像类似这样严重的问题还没有研究过
And quickly thereafter green pamphlets were distributed.
这过后不久 每个人手里就都有了一本绿宝书
We felt green was cheerful, but not too cheerful.
我们认为绿色让人感觉愉悦 并且不至于过分愉悦
Certainly better than red.
绝对好于红色
The pamphlets said there were 80 suicides a day in America - 30,000 a year.
绿宝书上写道： 在美国每天有80人自杀-一年3万
Cheese!
茄子！（另：也是大事件的意思）
lt alerted us to danger signals we couldn't help but look for.
宝书提醒我们对危险信号的警觉 那些我们无法求助却可以发现到的危险
Were the Lisbon girls' pupils dilated?
里斯本家的女孩们瞳孔有没有放大？
Had they lost interest in school activities and sports and hobbies?
他们是不是对学校活动、 体育运动和个人爱好失去兴趣了？
Had they withdrawn from their peers?
还是想从同龄人中抽身而出？
Hi, l'm Chase.
嗨，我是彻斯
l know who you are.
我知道你是谁
l've only been going to this school my whole life.
我这辈子就只上过这一所学校
You don't have to talk to me.
你不用非跟我说话
So, we have two different types of economics.
那么，我们有2种完全不同的经济模式
Of these different types the first one is called macroeconomics.
这其中的第一类我们称为宏观经济
Look.
看
She's laughing.
她在笑
He made her laugh. You never heard him say anything remotely intelligent!
他让她笑了，可是这么远， 根本听不清他说了什么鬼话！
The boys who talked with Lux were always stupid and terrible sources of information.
和拉克斯聊天的男孩子们总有些 愚蠢和恐怖的信息来源
..squeezebox. She's all right.
…手风琴。她真是棒
Let me tell you, she's the hottest girl in school.
我告诉你她是学校里最辣的女孩
You want to know what happened? Smell my fingers, man.
想知道发生了什么？ 闻我的手指吧，兄弟
No, she didn't talk about Cecilia.
不，她没谈什么西西莉亚
We weren't exactly talking, if you know what l mean.
确切的说，我们没谈什么 知道我什么意思吧？
The only reliable boy who got to know Lux was Trip Fontaine.
唯一可以相信十分了解拉克斯的人是 特里普 方丹
Who had recently lost his baby fat to the delight of girls and mothers alike.
一个最近刚减下自己的婴儿肥 来取悦了女孩和母亲们喜欢的男孩
l'm late again.
我又迟到了
Oh, come on!
哦，别这样
Thank you.
谢谢
All the girls at our school are in love with Trip.
学校里所有女生都爱特里普
All the girls, except Lux.
所有女生，除了拉克斯
Trip said his passion for Lux began when he went into the wrong History class.
特里普说他对拉克斯的热情 源自于一次误入了历史课的教室
As was his custom, he went out to smoke the marijuana
以他的习惯 总要出来抽点大麻
he took as regularly as a diabetic kid takes lnsulin.
他对这习以为常 就像糖尿病儿童打胰岛素一样
On this particular day, he avoided Mr Woodhouse by ducking into a class.
在这个特殊的日子 他为了躲避伍德豪斯先生而闪入最近的教室
She was the still point of the turning world.
她就像这旋转的世界上静止的一点
l never got over that girl. Never.
我永远也骗不了那姑娘，永远
l've loved a lot of ladies, but not like that... That was real.
我爱过的女人无数，但从没有那样儿过 那次是认真的
l'll never forget the first time l saw her.
我忘不了第一次见到她的时候
l didn't know what had hit me. l didn't know what to do.
不知道是什么让我心动 也不知道要做什么
Because it was so easy with all the other girls, but she wouldn't look at me.
因为和其他姑娘混在一起很容易 而她却连看都不看我一眼
l... l was never the kind to pursue. lf you know what l mean.
我…我从没那样追求过谁 你知道我什么意思
That girl drove me crazy, man.
那姑娘让我发疯，伙计
Mmm, yummy.
蓿好吃
Lux?
拉克斯？
Hey.
嘿
Look at it. lt's just meat on bread rolls.
看这儿，就只有面包卷儿加肉
Thanks, Mum.
谢了，妈妈
Trip's dad was little help.
特里普的爸爸帮了点忙
Well, first off, don't call her on the phone.
好，首先，不要给她打电话
lt's all... lt's all subtlety.
这是…这是很微妙的
lt's all nuance.
毫厘之微
Yeah. You just need to talk to her at school.
是啊，你只需要在学校和她聊聊
About anything. About the weather, or... school assignments.
聊什么都行，天气 或者…学校的功课
Anything for the chance to communicate with the language of eye contact.
任何东西 只为等待暗送秋波的机会
And project confidence.
要显得很自信
And keep the hair out of your eyes.
还有不要让头发挡住眼睛
Feel the vibe.
感觉它们的飘动就能知道
- Just do your stuff. - Yeah.
- 只管做好你的事 - 是啊
The word ''hurricane'' was the name given to Nature's strongest storm.
“飓风”这个词 用来形容自然界最强的风暴
A hurricane occurs when high-pressure
飓风发生于高压气流…
and low-pressure masses of air come into contact with one another.
…和低压气流相互发生碰撞的时候
There is often a significant difference in temperature between the two masses.
两种气压之间往往温差很大
One mass is warm, while the other is cold.
一种暖，一种寒
The warmer air rises and the cooler air falls.
暖空气上升，冷空气下降
Likewise, the low-pressure area slides down the sides of the high-pressure area.
同样地，低压部分向高压部分下面下滑
They swirl around one another,
相互盘旋
creating the beginnings of the storm.
形成风暴的雏形
With this footage, taken from US Navy weather patrol aircraft,
这些胶片，是美国海军气象监测飞机 拍摄到的画面
we can observe the high and low-pressure masses coming in contact with each other.
我们可以观察到高压和低压气流 开始相互碰撞
The result is a surging storm of tremendous strength
其结果是一场狂风暴雨
that strikes with forceful determination.
破坏力十足
Even though the hurricane is the most powerful storm known to us
即使我们了解到飓风是最强的风暴
it strikes large land areas such as continents or large islands.
但我们还不知道的是 它甚至能破坏像大陆和岛屿这样的陆上地区
and slowly dies.
并且它们去势缓慢
Mr Montgomery, his ass is grass.
蒙哥马利先生，有人“影响市容”
l want to ask you out.
我希望你能出来一下
Fat chance.
没门
First, l'll go over to your house and watch the tube.
首先，我会转到你家，打开电视
And then l'm gonna ask you out.
然后我就会要你出来
You're the stone fox.
你这个铁石心肠的狐狸
The hurricane. One of the most awesome and spectacular stories Nature has to offer.
飓风 自然界赐予的最可怕最特别的天气现象
- What channel is this? - Five.
- 这什么频道 - 5台
Oh. Let's see...
哦，来看看…
''Animals ln The Wild. Journey through the African Kalahari
“野生动物 非洲喀拉哈里沙漠之旅”
''and see animals in their natural habitat.''
“以及观看它们的自然栖息地”
l think that sounds nice, don't you?
听上去很不错，你们觉得呢？
This huge rainforest eventually gives way to grasslands
这片茂密的热带雨林最终 让位给了辽阔的草原
that stretch to the horizon in all directions - this is the Kalahari.
无论何方，都将延伸至地平线 ――这就是喀拉哈里沙漠
- Do you want some more pop? - Yeah, sure. Thank you.
- 还要喝点汽水吗？ - 好的，谢谢
Thanks.
多谢
The wildlife spectacle played out on these grasslands,
这片草原上展现出一派野生环境的景象，
and in recesses of the rainforest, is unparalleled anywhere on Earth.
和热带雨林深处一样 在世界各地，空前繁盛
Lux, put your feet down, honey.
拉克斯，把脚放下，宝贝儿
The Kalahari and its vast open sky provide a theatre for the life and death drama
喀拉哈里和它宽广辽阔的天空 为这生与死的表演提供了巨大的舞台
played out by the herds
参演的有这些牧群
and the great hunting cats that play on them.
还有捕食它们的猎手：猫科动物
Oh, my!
哦，我的天！
lt's getting so late. Honey...?
时间太晚了，宝贝儿们…？
- l said it's getting late. - Oh. Well, let's hit the TV button.
- 我说时间太晚了 - 哦，那，关了电视了
Right. Er...
好的，呃…
- OK. - Thank you.
- OK - 谢谢
- lt was nice to meet you Mrs Lisbon. - Yes.
- 很高兴见到你里斯本夫人 - 我也是的
- Good night. - See you.
- 晚安 - 再见
Bye.
拜
Goodbye.
再见
l've got to get back.
我得回去了，老爸会查房的
This is fourth period, l don't have you until fifth, do l?
现在是第4课时， 我们应该在第5课时见面，有什么不对吗？
l know. l'm not here for math today, sir.
我知道，我来这儿不是为了数学课 先生
l'm here to tell you that my intentions for your daughter are entirely honorable.
我在此想告诉您 我对您女儿的企图完全出于尊敬
- What might those intentions be? - To ask Lux to the Homecoming Dance.
- 你有什么企图？ - 我想邀请她参加舞会
Trip, why don't you sit down for a minute?
特里普，干嘛不坐下来呆会儿？
You see, my wife and l have certain rules.
你知道，我妻子和我制订了一些规矩
They were the rules for the older girls. l can't change them for the younger ones.
本来只是给我大女儿们的 现在看来也适用于小女儿了
Even if l wanted to, the wife wouldn't let me.
即便我同意，我太太也不会允许
So, if you want to come over and watch television again, that would be fine.
所以如果你想再来看电视，尽管来
But you cannot take Lux out. Especially not in a car.
不过如果你想邀拉克斯出去 根本不可能，特别是去开车兜风
So l'm sorry, son, that's just our policy.
那，很抱歉了，孩子 这就是我们的规矩
OK, sir. What if a bunch of us guys took all your daughters out in a group
OK，先生，如果是我们一帮男孩子 邀您家所有的女儿出去呢
and had them back by the time you said?
而且我们会按时把他们送回来
- Are you on the football squad, son? - Yes, sir.
- 你是橄榄球队的吗？ - 是的，先生
- What position? - Defence quarterback.
- 踢什么位置 - 防守四分位
Ah, good.
啊，很好
l was a... l was a safety in my day.
我曾经是…曾经是后卫
Well, that's a crucial position, sir.
喔，那个位置很关键，先生
- Nothing between you and the goal line. - Exactly!
- 您后面就是得分线阿 - 说得没错！
- Oh, well. - So the thing is, sir.
- 哦，这样的话 - 那么事情是这样的，先生
We've got the big game and then afterwards we've got the dance.
事情是这样，我们有场重要的比赛 之后要举行舞会
All the other guys are taking dates.
我要别的男生们都要带女伴来
You're good-looking. Lots of girls would go with you.
你长得很帅 喜欢你的女孩不少吧
l'm not interested in lots of girls, sir.
我对那些女孩不感兴趣
l'll take it up with the wife, Trip. Do what l can.
我要和太太商量一下，特里普 尽我所能吧
Thank you, sir.
谢谢您，先生
- lt's a craft. - Oh.
- 是手工制作的？ - 哦
Trip Fontaine and some of the boys in the football squad
特里普 方丹和球队的其他几个队员
have asked to take the girls to the Homecoming Dance.
邀请了几个女儿去参加“返校节”舞会
You know how l feel about that sort of thing.
你知道我对这类事情的看法
- l'm a chaperone at the dance. - Oh, please!
- 亲爱的，我将是舞会的监护人 （交际场监护少女的成年人） - 哦，求你了，妈妈！
Your father and l will discuss it later.
你父亲和我会找个时间商量这事的
Mr Fontaine, may l speak with you, please?
方丹先生，可以和你说几句话吗？
My wife and l have come to a decision about your request...
我太太和我关于你的请求做了一个决定
Yes!
耶！
l'm taking Lux Lisbon to Homecoming.
我们会带拉克斯 里斯本 来参加“返校节”舞会
l need three guys to take the other girls.
不过还需要三个人来邀请其他3位爱女
- l'll give you three joints, Trip. - Pick me. We can take my dad's Caddy.
- 我可以分你3片大麻，特里普 - 让我去吧，我可以把我爸的凯迪开去
You gotta pick me, Tripster.
你要选我 特里普斯特
Trip, man. You owe me.
特里普，你还欠我个人情呢
l saved your ass with Woodhouse that time.
上一次是我 让你免受伍德豪斯的皮肉之苦
- Thanks, Dad. - Who are the other boys?
- 谢谢，爸爸 - 别的男孩是谁？
Let's see. Parker Denton, Jake Conley - he's a good student, dear -
我们来看看，帕奇 丹顿、 杰克 康利-他可是好学生，亲爱的-
and Kevin Head.
还有凯文 海德
- Who's taking who? - They're going to raffle us off.
- 谁邀请谁阿？ - 他们要抽签决定了
lt didn't make any difference which dress the girls chose.
女孩选的衣服让我看没什么区别
Mrs Lisbon added an inch to the bust line and two to the waist and hems.
里斯本太太给每件衣服的胸围 都加大了一寸，腰围和摺边加大了2寸
The dresses became four identical sacks.
让那些衣服变成4条一模一样的“口袋”
- Everybody decent? - Yeah.
- 都穿好了吗？ - 是的
OK. Come on.
OK，来看这
Oh, l'm sorry. Here we go.
哦，我很抱歉，可以走了
Come on. Together.
来吧，一起
And cheddar cheese.
恩，鱼香茄子
Oh, it's so exciting!
哦，太令人兴奋了
- Are we ready? - Ready, man.
- 准备好了吗？ - 准备好了，伙计们
Let's do it.
来，行动吧
ln the end Parkie won because of the Cadillac,
最后赢的有帕奇 因为那辆凯迪拉克
Kevin Head, because he had the killer weed,
凯文 海德 因为他有那些要命的大麻
and Joe Hill Conley because he won all the school prizes -
还有乔 希尔 康利 因为他拥有所有学校的奖励――
which Trip thought would impress Mr and Mrs Lisbon.
特里普觉得 这会给里斯本夫妇留下个好印象
- Hello, boys. - Hello, Mrs Lisbon.
- 你们好，孩子们 - 您好，里斯本太太
- Come in. - Thank you.
- 请进 - 谢谢
- Who's driving? - l am.
- 谁开车？ - 是我
- How long have you had your license? - Two months. l was a learner for a year.
- 你什么时候获得的驾照？ - 两个月前。之前我已经学了一年了
The girls almost never go out in cars.
你们要知道 我们从没让姑娘们坐车出去过
- There's so many accidents. Be careful. - Oh, yes, ma'am.
- 交通事故太多了，一定要非常当心 - 哦，我们会的，夫人
OK. The third degree's over.
OK，最后的考验结束了
Girls!
姑娘们
- l'd better go. See you at the dance. - See you there, Mr Lisbon.
- 我要走了，舞会再见 - 呆会儿见，里斯本先生
Bye, dear.
拜，亲爱的
Girls. Come on down.
姑娘们，下来吧
The boys are here.
小伙子们都来了
We got white ones. We didn't know what you were wearing
我们买的是白色的花 虽然不知道你们穿什么
and the flower guy said that white would go with anything.
但那个花匠说了 白色配什么都合适
l'm glad you got white.
很高兴你买了白色的
Why don't you pin them on?
你们干吗不别上呢？
- There we go. - All right, let's do it.
- 成了 - 好的，我们走吧
Great.
非常好
Bye, Mum.
妈妈，再见
Oh, gosh, look! The car's there again!
哦，上帝，看啊！那车又停在那儿了
l'm sure Mr Lea's having an affair with her. He followed her into the laundry room.
我确信李先生和她有一腿 我看见他跟着她一起进了洗衣店
- He's so sad with that red nose. - Probably an alcoholic.
- 配上那红鼻头，他看起来真忧郁 - 很有可能是个酒鬼
- The Hesses are Nazis. - They're Nazi sympathizers.
- 那没准儿海斯一家是纳粹呢 - 他们是纳粹的支持者
They had a fit when Miss Schwartz tried to join the tennis club.
史沃特小姐想参加网球俱乐部的时候 他们还大吵了一架呢
Nice aluminum siding! Do they really think that looks OK?
铝制的墙板真不错！ 他们真以为那看上去还好吗？
- Mr Peters ordered that from TV. - lt's a Baldinos barbecue tree stump.
- 那可是彼得先生从电视上订购的 - 那是巴尔的摩烤肉用的树桩子？
l have never seen a barbecue on that thing!
我可从没见过在那上面烤肉的
Actually, it's an escape tunnel for the Shark.
实际上，那是鲨鱼老包的逃生通道
lt leads to the river and his speedboat.
直通到河边还有他的赛艇
Paul often goes there. He can get into anyone's basement through the sewers.
保罗经常去那儿 他能从下水道钻到任何人家里
- No way! - Yeah.
- 不可能！ - 是的
- Dad'll smell it on you. - No, l got mints.
- 爸爸会闻出来的 - 不会的，我嚼了薄荷的
- He'll smell it on your clothes. - l'll say they were smoking in the toilets.
- 他会从你衣服上闻出来 - 我可以解释说是在厕所里熏的
- Don't let it die a virgin. - That's gross.
- 别让它死如处子（指烟） - 这很重要的
Yeah, grow up, Conley.
好吧，成熟点，康德
- Do you want to dance? - Sure.
- 想跳支舞吗？ - 当然
Dance?
跳舞？
We've been having such lovely weather, don't you think?
今天的气氛真棒，你不觉得吗？
Yeah, we have... Nice.
是啊，我觉得…不错
Good evening. Could l have your attention for a moment?
晚上好，各位 请允许我讲几句话
l hope you're having a good time. lt sure looks like it.
希望大家度过一个美好的夜晚 当然 看来大家都很尽兴
The dance committee really outdid themselves this time.
舞会筹委会这次可谓是 用尽了浑身解数
l'd like to open the voting for Homecoming King and Queen.
我想是时候来选举今晚返校节舞会的 国王和王后了
The ballot box is over there, so please vote.
投票箱在那里，请大家积极投票
And we'll make the announcement in a little while. Thank you.
我们会在过会儿揭晓结果，谢谢大家
- Did anybody see you come in? - No.
- 有谁看见你进来吗？ - 没有
- What about you?
- 你呢？ - 也没有
You'll love it.
你会爱上它的
Peach schnapps.
桃子酿的杜松子酒
Babes love it.
孩子们都喜欢喝
That stuff tastes really good.
这货色还真够味
l don't want any, thanks.
我不要，谢谢
Go on, just a taste. A tiny taste.
来吧，就尝尝，一点点
Don't be such a goody-goody.
别装正经了
Don't swallow it.
不要一口吞下去
Can l have everyone's attention?
请大家注意了
l'd like you to put your hands together for this year's Kind and Queen...
我希望你们双手合十 共同欢迎今年的国王和王后就是…
Trip Fontaine and Lux Lisbon.
特里普 方丹和拉克斯 里斯本
l'm having the best time!
这是我度过的最愉快的夜晚！
Let's go for a walk.
一起走走吧
l'd better not. l've got to go back in a minute.
我想算了吧 我必须马上回去了
We can keep an eye on the car. They won't leave without us.
我们可以盯紧那汽车 他们不会丢下我们不管的
My dad...
我父亲…
Tell him you're putting the crown in your locker.
告诉他你把皇冠锁在柜橱了
- See that divot there? - Uh-huh?
- 嘿，看见那块草皮了吗？ - 恩哈？
That's where l reamed this guy today.
那是我今天摔倒那家伙的地方
- A cross body-block. - Really?
- 他可真结实 - 真的吗？
- Maybe they went home with your dad? - l doubt it.
- 或许他们跟你爸爸一起回家了 - 我不信
- We're cooked. - Luxy is, we're not.
- 我们被涮了 - 拉克斯被涮了，我们没有
Does anyone have any mints?
有谁带薄荷糖了没？
- Sorry. - No.
- 不好意思 - 没有
Bye, Parkie.
拜，帕奇
- We'll walk you to the door. - No, don't.
- 我们送你们到门边 - 不，不必了
- Why not? - Just don't.
- 为什么？ - 只是不需要
OK.
OK
Will you call me?
你会给我电话吗？
Absolutely!
当然！
Bye.
拜
- Bye.
- 拜
- Are you OK? - Where have you been?
- 你还好吧？ - 你们去哪了？
Look at the state of you! Get in the house!
瞧瞧你的样子 进屋去！
l walked home alone that night. l didn't care how she got home. lt was weird.
那晚我独自走回了家 我并没在乎她是怎么回去的，这很奇怪
l mean, l liked her. l liked her a lot. But out there on the field...
我是说，我喜欢她，非常喜欢 可是在球场上的时候…
lt was just different then.
感觉就变得不一样了
That was the last time l saw her.
那是我最后一次见到她
You know, most people will never taste that kind of love.
你知道大多数人不会尝试那样的恋爱
But at least l tasted it once, right?
但至少我试过了，对吗？
lt's time for your six o'clock group meeting.
6点小组会议的时间到了
Given Lux's failure to make curfew, everyone expected a crackdown.
由于拉克斯没有按时回家 大家都知道会受到严厉的制裁
But few anticipated it would be so drastic.
但是没人能料到是如此严重的后果
The girls were taken out of school and Mrs Lisbon shut the house
姑娘们辍学了 里斯本夫人也屋门紧闭
in maximum-security isolation.
以保证最大安全限度的与世隔绝
She did more than taking the girls out of school.
除了让女儿们辍学 她还做了更过分的事
That Sunday, after a spirited church sermon.
那个周日， 作完教堂的礼拜后
Mrs Lisbon made Lux destroy her records.
里斯本夫人逼迫拉克斯 销毁了她所有的唱片
Now!
现在！
But, Mum...
可是，妈…
This is final, Luxy.
这就是后果，拉克斯
- That's not fair. - l said now.
- 这不公平 - 我说了，现在！
Now, Luxy!
现在，拉克斯！
Come on.
快点
Kiss. Please don't make me do this.
这可是“KISS”的，不要逼我这么做
Burn it.
烧了它
Oh, Mum, Aerosmith! Come on, please don't make me burn this.
哦，妈，“Aerosmith”！ 我求你，别让我烧了它
Please...
求你…
What's that smell?
是什么味道啊？
All right, that'll do for now. Give me these... Give me these.
好吧，现在就烧这些吧 把剩下的给我…给我
l'll put them in the trash.
我要把他们丢到垃圾桶去
This was when we began seeing Lux making love on the roof with random men.
从这以后，我们开始发现 拉克斯经常在屋顶上和各种男人调情
- ls she naked? - You can't tell.
- 她没穿衣服吗？ - 这很难说
Get it focused.
调好焦距
- Will you stop? Wait your turn. - What are they doing?
- 你能不能不折腾了，等着会轮到你 - 他们在干什么？
They're rolling around up there.
他们在上面打滚呢
Hold on. She's on him. He's rubbing his hands through her hair.
等等，她骑到他身上了 他在用手指抚摸她的头发
- Let me look. - No. No, it's my telescope, Chase.
- 让我看看 - 不，不，这是我的望远镜，彻斯
- Yes and what else? - That man's in a burger chalet uniform.
- 好吧，还看到什么？ - 那男的穿着汉堡包房的制服
Let me see.
让我看看
Yeah. You never think that those guys ever get lucky.
是啊， 谁会想到那种男人也会有这样的福气
Then she asks me if what we'd just done was dirty.
然后她问我 我们刚做的事是不是很脏
l knew what to say. l said no.
我知道要说什么，我说不
Then she goes, ''You like me, don't you?''
然后她接着说， “你喜欢我，是吗？”
l didn't say anything. lt's best to keep chicks guessing.
我什么都不说了 这时候最好让“雏儿”们猜猜
Chase, honey. Come practice your violin before dinner.
彻斯，宝贝儿 晚饭前回来练练小提琴
You're not going to believe it. Lux is on the roof again tonight!
你们没法相信 拉克斯今晚又上屋顶了
- Her hands are moving down. - l gotta see this.
- 她的手在向下摸 - 我要看看这个
- This is beautiful. - Now she's on top of him.
- 好美 - 现在她在他上面了
- What's she doing, man? - Wait.
- 她在干什么，伙计？ - 等着
Now they're done. He's getting up.
现在他们完事了，那男的起来了
- That's it? - That was quick.
- 就这些 - 也太快了
...plus one. And if the exponential is time, then you'd have as you approach...
…加上一，如果幂指数是时间函数 那么你会得到如你计算的…
Oh, good morning. Have we photosynthesized our breakfast today?
哦，早上好 我们今天光合作用的早餐味道如何？
- Hello, Ronald. - Hi, Harry.
- 你好，罗纳德 - 嗨，哈里
Your daughters haven't been at school for over two weeks.
你女儿们已经两个多星期没有上学了
Have you checked out back?
你去后面查过了吗？
They've found a new Math teacher.
他们已经找到一个新的算术老师
- He'll have to get another job. - l know.
- 他要去找另一份工作了 - 我晓得
How long can those girls be cooped up like that?
那些姑娘们还要被拘禁多久？
Go away. This is our tree.
离远点，这是我们的树
Girls, girls... lt's a little late. This tree is dead.
姑娘们… 你们来晚了，这棵树死了
- Why don't you leave it up to Nature? - lf we did, there'd be no trees left.
- 为什么不能让它自生自灭呢？ - 我们要是那么做，这的树都会死的
That's what it's going to be like anyway.
或许本来就应该这样
lf they didn't bring the fungus from Europe, this wouldn't have happened.
如果没人从欧洲传入菌菇 现在也不会有人吃那东西
OK. Let's go.
OK，让我们继续
No?
不？
That's it. l have an order to cut down your elm tree,
是这样，我们有令在先 一定要伐倒这棵榆树
but your kids won't let us.
但是您的孩子阻挠我们这么做
- How do you know it's sick. - Believe me, it's dead for Christsake.
- 你怎么知道他病了 - 相信我，以基督的名气起誓，它确实死了
- Arbotect is a less aggressive therapy. - lt doesn't work.
- 你们试过虫媒疗法吗？我女儿从一篇杂志上 看到说这办法对树本身的侵害比较小 - 没有用的
- l leave that tree there, they'll all go. - They could anyway.
- 如果我把这棵树留下，其他的就遭殃了 - 他们可以活下来
Look, l don't want to call the police.
听着，我可不想叫警察
Our daughters are standing on our lawn. Since when is that a crime?
我的女儿站在自己家的草坪上 什么时候这也成罪过了？
Clive. See those girls in their nighties? That's the shot that l want.
克利夫，看到那些穿睡衣的姑娘了吗？ 那就是我想要的镜头
Honey, you'll have to move forward. l want those girls in their nighties.
亲爱的，你必须把车开过去 我需要拍那些穿睡衣的姑娘们
- Let's back up. - Give me some more slack.
- 倒退一点 - 再让我多放松一会儿
- There you go. ls that good? - Great.
- 听你的 行了吗？ - 很好
Four sisters of Cecilia Lisbon,
您看到的是西西莉亚 里斯本的四个姐姐
the teenager whose suicide last summer focused awareness on a national problem,
这个去年夏天自杀的女孩 引起了世人的关注，
put their own lives in jeopardy by trying to protect the elm that Cecilia so dearly loved.
而今天她的姐姐们正在用生命来捍卫 他们的小妹生前最喜爱的一棵榆树
The circles under your eyes come out when it's overcast, so you need to wear...
天阴的时候，你眼底就会出现圆环 所以你要配戴…
For the next few weeks we hardly saw the girls at all.
以后的几个星期里 我们根本见不到姑娘们
Joe didn't call Therese as he had promised.
乔食言了，他没给特里斯打电话
And Lux never spoke to Trip again.
而拉克斯也不再和特里普说话了
You're the stone fox.
你真是只铁石心肠的狐狸
The girls' only contact with the world was through the catalogues they ordered.
姑娘们只能通过他们订的那些商品目录 和外面的世界交流
lt filled their mailbox with pictures of high-end fashions
他们的邮箱里塞满了流行时尚的图片
and brochures for exotic vacations.
和去异国度假的小册子
Unable to go anywhere, they travelled in their imaginations to Siamese temples,
因为哪儿也去不了 他们只好在想象中遨游暹罗古寺
or past an old man with a leaf broom tidying a moss-carpeted speck of Japan.
或者是从一位日本老人身旁经过 看着他用扫帚打扫附在青苔的尘埃
We ordered the same catalogues and hiked through dusty passes with the girls.
我们订了同样的目录 也跟随着，去“步他们的后尘”
Stopping every now and then to help them with their backpacks.
我们会时不时稍作逗留 帮他们打点行囊
Placing our hands on their warm, moist shoulders,
也会把手放在他们温暖潮湿的香肩
and gazing off at the fire sunsets.
一同凝视夕阳西下
We drank tea with them in a water pavilion.
还会于水榭中共品淡茶一杯
We did whatever we wanted.
我们随心所欲
Cecilia hadn't died. She was a bride in Calcutta.
西西莉亚并没有死 她只是远嫁到加尔各答罢了
The only way we felt close to the girls was through these impossible excursions
我们只能用这种虚无的“远足” 来“亲近”姑娘们
which have scared us forever,
这让我们后来一直惊恐有余
making us happier with dreams than wives.
可也会做些美梦 比跟爱人在一起还要快乐的美梦
Collecting everything we could of theirs, the Lisbon girls wouldn't leave our minds,
我们尽所能收集他们的一切 里斯本女孩们永远占据着我们的心
but they were slipping away.
不过也愈行愈远
The colors of their eyes faded along with the exact location of their dimples.
他们眼睛的颜色渐渐褪去 同样消却的还有那些痦子和酒窝
From five they had become four, and they were all living in the dead...
从五个人变成四个 他们生活变得死气沉沉
becoming shadows.
暗无天日
We were losing them when the girls contacted us.
姑娘们联系我们的时候 我们快要完全地失去他们了
One long. Two short.
一长，两短
One long. Have you got that?
一长，收到吗？
- That's it. - OK.
- 就是这些 - OK
Help.
救命
Send.
发送
Bo... Bo.
Bo... Bo
- Bobo? - Bobo. That's it... Bobo.
- Bobo？ - Bobo，没错…Bobo
''Help. Send Bobo.'' l thought you knew Morse code!
“救命，发送Bobo” 我以为你懂摩尔斯电码呢！
There's something here for you.
给你一样东西
l got one, too.
我也有一件
We racked our brains for a way of contacting them.
（不管你是谁，告诉特里普，我看不起他，他是缩头乌龟 你猜得到的人上） 我们绞尽脑汁 寻找可以联系他们的方式
Tom suggested we fly a kite with a message alongside the house.
汤姆建议说做个写好内容的风筝 放飞到他家附近
But that had logistical problems.
可这根本不符合逻辑
ln the end, the answer was simple - we called them on the telephone.
最后，我们选了最简单的办法- 打电话
727 8221 .
727 8221
Get ready.
准备
- Hello? - Go!
- 喂？ - 开始！
Call us. 727 0487.
打给我们 727 0487
Shit. lt's them.
妈的，是他们
- l'm going home. See you tomorrow. - See you later.
- 我回家了，明天见 - 回头见
- We're suffocating. - Lux, you're safe here.
- 我们快憋闷死了 - 拉克斯，这儿是最安全的
l can't breathe.
我没法呼吸了
No answer.
没回话 （蒂姆，明天子夜，等我们信号）
- What time is it? - Any time now.
- 几点了 - 时间是现在
- Guys, there it is. - What?
- 伙计们，看那儿 - 什么？
Yeah, it's them.
是的，是他们
Let's go.
出发
l've got the keys to my mum's car.
我有我妈的车钥匙
Maybe we should knock.
或许我们应该敲门
We're here.
我们来了
lt's about time. We've been waiting for you guys.
时间差不多 我们等着你们呢
We've got a car. We'll take you anywhere you want to go.
我们搞了辆车 你们想去哪儿都成
lt's a Cougar. lt's got a big trunk.
是辆“美洲狮”，大得像卡车
- Can l sit up front? - Sure.
- 我能做前面吗？ - 当然
Which one of you is going to sit next to me?
你们谁愿坐我旁边呢？
- Where are your parents? - Asleep.
- 你爸妈呢？ - 睡了
- What about your sisters? - They're coming.
- 其他人呢？ - 马上就来
Come on. lt's late.
快点，很晚了
Wait five minutes. We have to wait until my parents are asleep.
再等5分钟 我们要等爸妈睡熟了才行
They take forever. My mum's an insomniac.
他们总醒着 我妈有失眠症
We'd better take our car, there's more room.
我们最好开我们的车 空间更多些
- Think you can handle a station wagon? - Sure. lt's not a stick, is it?
- 你能开旅行车吗？ - 当然，不是手动档，是吧？
- No. - Yeah, no problem.
- 不是 - 那就好，没问题
- Will you let me steer? - Sure.
- 我可以驾驶吗？ - 可以
We should go. l just heard something. lt could be your mum.
我们进去吧 好象有点动静，可能是你妈
Come on in.
进来吧
l'll go wait in the car. You guys wait here for my sisters.
我去车里等 你们在这儿等他们来
These girls make me crazy. lf l just felt one of them once!
这些女孩会让我疯狂的 只感觉了其中之一就让我受不了了
What?
什么？
We would never be sure about the sequence of events.
我们永远无法确信 事情竟会如此进展
We argue about it still.
直到现在都还在争论
Most likely, Bonnie had died while we were waiting in the living room
最大的可能是 我们等在客厅想象高速公路美景的时候
dreaming of highways.
邦妮死了
Mary put her head in the oven shortly thereafter.
过后不久 玛莉把头伸进了烤箱
Therese, stuffed with sleeping pills, was gone by the time we got there.
特里斯，吞下了大把的安眠药 我们到时，已经气绝
Lux was the last to go.
拉克斯是最后一个
lt's four o'clock on Sunday afternoon. Do you know where your children are?
现在是星期日的午后四点 您知道您的孩子们现在何处吗？
Bonnie, the younger Lisbon sister...
邦妮，里斯本家最小的妹妹…
Therese Lisbon, a horse-lover, has written to...
特里斯 里斯本, 骑马爱好者，曾写信给…
Mary wanted to be a cheerleader, but her mother wouldn't let her.
玛莉相当啦啦队长 但是她母亲不同意
..suicide in their house...
…他们家中的自杀案件…
- l wasn't able to express the anger l felt. - ..Lydia Perl, Channel Eight News.
- 我无法解释我心中的愤怒 - …莉迪亚 珀尔，8频道新闻报道
None of my daughters lacked for any love.
我的女儿都不缺少关爱
There was plenty of love in our house.
我们家里充满了爱，到处都是
l never understood why.
我也不明白为什么
After the suicides, Mr and Mrs Lisbon gave up any attempt to lead a normal life.
女儿自杀以后，里斯本先生和夫人 放弃了过正常人生活的尝试
They had Mr Hadley pack up the house,
他们拜托哈得利先生收拾他们的房子
and sell the furniture in a garage sale.
以旧货价卖掉了所有家具
Mr Lisbon sold the house to a young couple from Boston.
里斯本夫妇把房子 卖给了一对从波士顿来的年轻夫妇
We, of course, took the family photos that were put out with the trash.
我们，当然还是拍了几张这家里的照片 虽说只剩下些垃圾
ln the end, we had pieces of the puzzle, but gaps still remained.
最终，我们拥有这块“拼图”的大多数碎片 可是仍有空缺
Oddly-shaped emptiness, mapped by what surrounded them,
那空缺形状怪异地被别的东西包围着
like countries we couldn't name.
好像是一些我们叫不上名字的国家
What lingered after them was not life,
他们之后苟延残喘的并非生命
but the most trivial list of mundane facts -
而是众多不足道矣的凡尘琐事――
a clock ticking on the wall,
那墙上滴答作响的钟
a room dim at noon,
那晌午晦暗的房间
the outrageousness of a human being thinking only of herself.
以及那些自私暴敛的人类
We began the impossible process of trying to forget them.
我们开始经历一些不真实的过程 来试图忘掉他们
Our parents were able to do this,
我们父母可以做的到
returning to their tennis foursomes and cocktails as though they'd seen it all before.
他们回到网球赛场或者鸡尾酒会 好像他们以前见到过类似的东西一样
lt was full-fledged summer again -
又是一个飞逝的夏天――
over a year after Cecilia had slit her wrists spreading the poison in the air.
距离西西莉亚割腕 并大肆散布这“消息”的时间已一年有余
A spill at the plant increased the lake's phosphates and produced algae
这些植物溅落出的东西 增加了湖中磷的成分，并导致水藻滋生
so that the swamp's smell filled the air infiltrating the genteel mansions.
以致于这“沼泽”的味道传到空气中 渗透到上层社会的宫邸里
Debutantes cried at coming out in a season remembered for its bad smell.
涉世之初的人们要求辟出一个季节 来纪念这种腐败的味道
The O'Connors ingeniously made
奥康纳一家极聪明的 将纪念女儿爱丽丝成人的舞会主题
the theme of their daughter Alice's debutante party ''Asphyxiation''.
定为“窒息”
Like everyone else, we went to forget about the Lisbon girls.
和其他人一样， 我们慢慢忘记了里斯本家的姑娘
She'll give him a heart attack.
她会让他犯病的
Hi, Parkie.
嗨，帕奇
How about the acting bug?
要是那臭虫装死怎么办？
l caught it from Kinky.
我从“卷毛”那里抓到过一只
And l want to announce tonight that next fall Alice is going to school in Newhaven.
今晚我要宣布一件事，这个秋天 爱丽丝将会到纽海文去上学
l hear they have a great grammar school up there.
我听说他们有一流的语法学校
ln fact, Sam's father built it, didn't he?
事实上，是山姆的父亲开的，对吧？
The hospital, Paul.
是医院，保罗
We're so proud of Alice. We couldn't be prouder.
我们为爱丽丝感到骄傲 没有比这更骄傲的了
Here's to her.
为她干杯
l've had it. Goodbye cruel world.
我受够了 再见吧，残忍地世界
No, no, no! You don't understand me. l'm a teenager, l got problems.
不、不、不！你没听明白 我是个小孩子，我有烦恼
So much has been said about the girls over the years,
多年来关于女孩们的流言仍不绝于耳
but we have never found an answer.
可我们还是没能发现答案
lt didn't matter how old they had been,
其实，他们那时有多大
or that they were girls,
或者他们怎样扮演女孩这个角色的 对我们都无关紧要
but only that we had loved them.
重要的是我们爱过他们
And that they still do not hear us calling them out of those rooms
他们原来没听到，现在仍旧也 听不到我们在屋外的呼喊―
where they went to be alone for all time.
―那个他们一辈子与世隔绝的屋外
We will never find the pieces to put them back together.
至于那块空缺的碎片， 我们永远也无法找到，永远也无法填补上去